<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edtech on Dave Rosborough</title>
    <link>http://edu.rosborough.ca/categories/edtech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edtech on Dave Rosborough</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:24:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edu.rosborough.ca/categories/edtech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Schoology - Audio recordings for assignments</title>
      <link>http://edu.rosborough.ca/schoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:24:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edu.rosborough.ca/schoology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have taken a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schoology.com&#34;&gt;Schoology&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but have generally stuck with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmodo.com&#34;&gt;EdModo&lt;/a&gt; for my classroom LMS.  For the upcoming year, however, I will be trying Schoology for one big reason: &lt;em&gt;audio recording in the iOS / Android app&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the iOS app from Schoology is more mature than the comparable EdModo one.  It seems to be well connected and allows the user access to photos, videos, etc when submitting assignments.  For me, however, the big feature is being able to do a quick audio recording &lt;em&gt;right in the app&lt;/em&gt;.  As a choir teacher, this means I can construct simple singing exercises, and the student needs nothing more than their phone or tablet and the Schoology app to complete the assignment.  This simplifies the workflow for students significantly, which is great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside is that the student cannot see the assignment information while they are making their recording.  This is a minor downside for my situation (where the student will likely be working from printed music for the assignments anyways), but could be a bigger issue for, say, language teachers wanting students to read a passage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>